Joshua Cave

in linkedin.com/in/joshuacave

nerdy.co.nz

Summary

A passionate software developer with 7 years of experience in full-stack applications. Building solutions in both **C#** and **Golang** and **VueJS** on the front-end.

Having worked in contract positions for the last 3 years, I realize how much I miss working with other developers and like-minded people. I am now seeking a new opportunity with a strong team focus that will provide the next big challenge in my career.

Experience

Digital Lead - Coastgroup

Feb 2019 - Present

Originally a client of NERDY through Displayworks. I was brought on to continue work on Shredder, an internal job system I built for Displayworks, retrofitting and improving it for use in other companies within the group.

Built on **Vue.js** and **Golang** I have since integrated with both **Gsuite** and **MYOB Accountright** drastically improving the workflow of the account managers.

I have also been in charge of improving their digital presence and launching new e-commerce sites on **BigCommerce**.

Responsibilities include:

- Working directly with managers of both Exhibition Hire Services and Show Light & Power retrofitting Shredder to suit their more event orientated businesses
- Launching new websites on BigCommerce for Exhibition Hire Services & Displayways
- Improving SEO and liaising with Pure SEO to improve digital presence across the group
- Working closely with designers and other team members on new content

Contract Developer - Pengellys

Apr 2017 - Present

Contracting on a weekly basis to Pengellys maintaining and improving their bespoke logistics system built on .NET and Classic ASP - with over 20 years worth of custom code that can prove pretty challenging. I work face to face with the client hot coding new ideas and deploying changes daily with an "iterate fast and release often" approach.

Noteworthy Features:

- Health & safety system
- Task and Corrective Action Report system
- Interactive KPI reports
- Client area with an interactive world map showing imports and exports and detailed product info
- A web-based document management system

Director - NERDY Nov 2017 - Feb 2019

Going at it alone. I found a niche in building job/invoicing systems for a small group of clients. I set out with NERDY using a completely new tech stack. Building full stack applications using **Vue.js** with **Golang**, backed by RESTful apis using **Postgres** and **Redis** for storage.

Applications are hosted on self-managed VPS using **Dokku** and **Git** continuous deployments.

Lessons:

- Completely new tech stack
- Confidence to prototype and pitch ideas
- More accurate view on how long projects take
- More goal orientated mindset
- Better self-awareness/discipline

Lastly, I launched <u>Relapse</u> the time tracking application for OSX using **Node.js**, **Electron**, **Vue.js** and **HTML5 canvas**.

Senior Developer - beweb

Oct 2013 - Nov 2017

A web development company specializing in bespoke websites for digital agencies and key clients. Websites are built using **.NET** and backed by **SQL server**. I started as a junior developer and grew through the ranks, taking on every aspect of working with a close nit group of developers in a fast-paced environment.

I was also directly involved with the launch of a **Cordova** based mobile application <u>Speaking Email</u> - a subscription based email client that reads your email out loud.

Responsibilities included:

- Mentoring / Pair Programming with junior developers
- Liaising directly with clients
- Code reviews
- Maintenance of Codelib (core code library)
- Quoting / scoping new projects

I still have a great working relationship with beweb and work on a contract basis.

Lecturer - United Institute of Technology

Jan 2013 - Dec 2013

I was approached by Unitec to teach Software Applications in the Certificate in Information Technology.

The course covered Excel, Access and Word, with a focus on introducing students to basic logic using conditional statements in Excel and teaching them about relational databases in Access.

This role required me to be very confident in communicating ideas and concepts to a large group of people and be well organised in preparing course material and keeping the students within schedule.

I was voted third highest rated lecturer across all departments at United during Semester 1 2013 on a student run website critiquing the courses and lecturers at United.

Education

Unitec - Bachelor in Computing Systems

2013

Unitec – Diploma in Information Technology and Support

2009 - 2010

Gained award for top Diploma student in Information Technology and Support 2010

Unitec - Certificate in Information Technology

2009